关注新浪微博
@MAET字幕组
中英特效字幕
只为爱电影的你
MAET字幕组原创译制
特效
塔可
翻译
梅花Q Hrafntinna Nobody
校对
竹林上人 larsen
以下为电影《落水狗》片段
橙先生
Mr. Orange.
粉先生
Mr. Pink.
白先生
Mr. White.
快他妈给我滚开  快点
Get the fuck out of the way! Move!
快点   快他妈滚开
Move! Get the fuck out of the way!
对不起  我现在太他妈害怕了
Sorry, I'm fucking scared right now.
抱住我好么
Will you please hold me?
好吧
Okay.
好 我抱住你了
Here, I got you.
你是打算就这么叫唤一天么 小狗狗
Are you gonna bark all day,little doggie?
还是动点儿真格的
Or are you gonna bite?
嘿 你们两个混蛋 妈的 冷静点儿
Hey look, you two assholes,calm the fuck down!
嘿 闪开
Hey, back off!
啥 你以为在闹着玩儿么
What, we're on a playground here?
就我一个懂行的么
Am I the only professional?
只能他妈倒个立
Have to do a fucking handstand?
我也不知道今晚为何在这儿
♪ Well, I don't know why I came here tonight ♪
歌曲 Stuck in the middle with you
有种感觉 好像有事不大对劲儿
♪ I got a feeling that something ain't right ♪
好怕会从椅子上摔了下来
♪ I'm so scared in case I fall off my chair ♪
下楼梯的姿势又该怎么摆
♪ And I'm wondering how I'll get down the stairs ♪
该死的 乔
God damn you Joe.
别逼我
Don't make me do this.
拉里 别他妈的拿枪指着我爹
Larry, stop pointing that fucking gun at my dad!
狼群
这里越来越没意思了
It gets boring around here.
低俗小说
我把整部电影的台词都写了下来
I write down the lines of the entire film.
每个角色说的话
What each character says.
我们总是说自己喜欢电影的台词
We always say lines from some of our favorite films.
有时候会想 为什么我们自己不拍点那样的电影
And we kind of thought why don't we do those films?
来演那些角色
Be those characters?
这有《斗士》
Got The Fighter.
《低俗小说》有不少
Pulp Fiction has a lot of characters.
床上剧本分别为《低俗小说》《好家伙》《笑破铁幕》《斗士》《黑暗骑士》三部曲
我们能演的角色
That all of us can play in.
《落水狗》太完美了
Reservoir Dogs is a perfect one.
给我一种 我还活着的感觉
It makes me feel like I'm living, sort of.
因为 就像是有某种魔力似的
'Cause it's kind of magical, a bit.
这就是壮丽的W.O.O.D （可能是木材厂区）
This is the mighty W.O.O.D.
这家合法经营的木材厂传来
A usable licensed lumber (dealer)
本句话为电视插播 可能翻译意思不准 请见谅
树木倒下的声音
has the sound of the falling tree.
九点半了
It's 9:30!
要是没有电影 生活会相当的无聊
If I didn't have movies,life would be pretty boring.
也就没有活下去的意义了
And there wouldn't be any point to go on, you see?
所以电影打开了另一个世界
So movies opened up another world,
但我一直觉得自己会是个孤独的人
But I always thought I would be a lonely person,
孑然一身
live in solitude.
只是我这么觉得而已
That was just my view.
电影里也有很多…
SO... and it's shown a lot in movies too...
害羞 孤单的孩子
The shy, lonely kid...
我小时候就是这样
That was my childhood.
印度教教派
克利须那教
The Hare Krishna religion.
神克利须那 和他每个妻子
The God is Krishna,and he has ten children
都生了十个孩子
with every wife that he has,
我们父亲  就特别信这个
And our father was, like,enthralled by that.
他就有种想法
So he had this idea of like, you know,
建立一个大的团体 我们自己的群落
having a big group like our own community,
自己的种族
our own race here.
就差不多像是部落一样
It's almost like a tribe that you have.
让这儿的所有人都留长发
And we're gonna have all of them grow long hair
用地球上最古老的语言 梵文
and I'm gonna give them all names
给他们起名字
of the oldest language on the planet... Sanskrit.
那个是戈文达 那个是纳拉亚纳
There's Govinda,there's Narayana,
奎师那 加哥迪沙  穆昆达 薄伽梵
Krsna, Jagadisha,Mukunda, Bhagavan,
还有我们妹妹 毗湿奴
and our sister, Visnu.
她有点儿跟别人不一样
She's sort of special in a way,
她基本上是活在她自己的世界里
like she almost is in a world of her own.
他本来还准备再生三个孩子
And he had names for three more children
名字也起好了  不过不巧
that he wanted,but as it so happens,
我妈妈上了年纪
my mother caught up with age
不能再生育了
and then she couldn't have children anymore.
我喜欢喝咖啡
I love coffee, yeah.
我喜欢每天喝上个五六杯咖啡
I like take six or five cups of coffee a day.
我哥哥列了个他最喜欢的三十部电影的名单
You know, my brother made his own top 30 list.
其实我也有这想法
I actually had my own ideas
所以我也列了一张
so I made my own list.
我们都认为《教父》和《教父2》
All of us agree that The Godfather I and II
应该排在第一
is number one.
- 我觉得排第二的应该是《刺杀肯尼迪》 - 同意
- Number 2 for me is JFK. - I agree.
- 《刺杀肯尼迪》 - 我第二喜欢的电影
- JFK. - My second favorite movie.
第三是《乱世佳人》
Number three for me is Gone With the Wind.
我喜欢《乱世佳人》
I love Gone With the Wind.
还有《指环王》
And The Lord of the Rings.
有谁会不喜欢《指环王》
Who doesn't like The Lord of the Rings ?
所以我把它排在第四
So I put it fourth.
这放的 都是各种各样的电影
All we have here is a variety of different...
有《公民凯恩》 还有《卡萨布兰卡》
See we have Citizen Kane and Casablanca，
大多数人都认为它是
which most people consider
有史以来最伟大的电影
to be the greatest movies ever made.
大家一直都公认
Most people consider
《公民凯恩》是最好的
Citizen Kane number one all the time.
我们还有不少恐怖电影
We have a collection of horror films
像《孽欲杀人夜》 《隔山有眼》
like,Manhunter,The Hills Have Eyes,
《蓝丝绒》
Blue Velvet
披头士
蛋头博士
好听么
Is that a good sound?
披头士
蛋头博士
非常好听
That is a good sound.
父母不怎么支持我们
My parents didn't always encourage us
和外界交流
to communicate with society.
所以我们有点儿与世隔绝
So we were kind of shut off,
一直待在这间
always lived in this apartment in New York,
纽约曼哈顿岛下东区的公寓里
lower east side,Manhattan,
我们从来没真正和别人交流过
and we never really communicated with people.
我们父亲教育我们不要和陌生人说话
We were taught by our father not to talk to strangers,
就是那一套说法  不过还不止这样
you know,the whole thing,but it was farther than that.
甚至 连看其他人都不行
It was like,don't even look at people.
我们没交过朋友   在家自学
We didn't make any friends.We were home-schooled.
我父母担心那样会危险
Also the fear of that my parents had
因为这是纽约 什么事都可能发生
because it's New York anything can happen.
我父亲有点儿 我感觉他有点儿太过了
My father kind of...I felt he overdid it,
他有点 太担心 太关心了
like he was almost too worried, too concerned.
冬天 我们基本上就从不出门
Winter, we'd literally almost never go out.
每年出门的次数都不固定
Every year was unpredictable.
夏天 我们出门的机会
In the summer,there was more chance
就多点儿
of us getting out.
有时候一年出去了九次
Sometimes we'd go out nine times a year,
有时候就一次
sometimes once...
还有一年  我们整年都没出去
And at one particular year,we never got out at all.
我总是愿意把我们童年比作
I always like metaphorically described our childhood
他就像是
as like him being the, uh...
地主 我们就像是他地里干活的
landowner and us the people who work on the land.
不过 要是再形象点儿比喻
But if you want a more dramatic setting,
我们就是在坐牢
we were in a prison.
没错
Yeah.
到了晚上 牢房就会锁起来
And at night,our cells would lock up.
他就是监狱长
He was the warden.
这么说也行
If you say so.
告诉他们
Tell them.
西德尼 西德尼 过来 你是知道我的
Sidney, Sidney, come on,you know me.
墙上海报为
《月光光心慌慌》《外太空杀人小丑》《快乐万圣节》
《惊魂记》《断头谷》《鬼玩人》《恐怖南瓜头》《恶魔娃娃》等
西德尼 看着我
Sidney, look at me!
过来
Come on!
男孩女孩不管你几岁
♪ Boys and girls of every age ♪
电影《圣诞夜惊魂》插曲 this is Halloween
演唱者：玛丽莲曼森
想不想看点儿奇怪的事儿
♪ Wouldn't you like to see something strange? ♪
跟着我们你就能看见
♪ Come with us and you will see ♪
这是我们的万圣之城
♪ This, our town of Halloween ♪
这就是万圣节 这就是万圣节
♪ This is Halloween this is Halloween ♪
万圣节 万圣节  万圣节 万圣节
♪ Halloween, Halloween Halloween, Halloween ♪
小镇就是我们的家
♪ In this town we call home ♪
大家欢唱南瓜颂
♪ Everyone hail to the pumpkin song ♪
万圣节 万圣节 万圣节 万圣节
♪ Halloween, Halloween,Halloween, Halloween ♪
万圣节 万圣节
♪ Halloween, Halloween...♪
- 谁？ - 披萨男
- Yes? - Mr. Pizza guy.
- 谁？- 披萨男
- Who? - Mr. Pizza guy.
空空先生 打个招呼
Mr. Hollow, say hello.
猛鬼街中的鬼 被称为 "鬼王"
好的 鬼面弗莱迪克鲁格
Yes, face man Freddy Kruger!
我的小萨米你在哪呢
And now where's my little Sammy
噢 嘿
Oh, hey.
这就是全部剧本
This is the whole script.
这里大概有
it's about...
116页
116 pages.
呃 你进楼里来的时候
Uh, when you came in the building,
没什么事儿吧
Was everything okay?
是的
Yeah.
- 没人去烦你？ - 没有
- Nobody bothered you? - No.
好 我就确定一下
Okay, I'm just checking.
你其实是我们邀请的第一位客人
You're actually our first，guests to be invited over.
这是真的 没骗你
That's true, actually.
不好意思 洋葱有点儿…（呛眼）
Excuse me, the onions...
- 我闻到了迷迭香和百里香的味道 - 对
- I can smell，the rosemary and the thyme. - Yeah.
很香
it smells very nice.
这些酱应该够了吧
I just hope this is enough sauce.
你尝尝看这个酱 看看还缺什么不
I need you to taste the sauce,see what's missing,
还需不需要再加点
If I can add something else or...
需要再加点什么吗？
Should I add something else?
要不再加点儿牛至 行么
Maybe a little more oregano.It's okay?
- 很好 - 那好
- That's perfect.- It's okay.
- 嗯 - 好 很好
- Yeah. - Okay, good.
- 那我们点火吧 - 非常好
- We can get this fire started.- That's very good.
有不少人议论他们
You know, there's people who talk about them.
为什么你们不去公共学校
Why don't you go to public school?
你们应该去公共学校
You should go to public school,
你们都没有社交生活
and, you know, you're missing all the socialization,
虽然我上过学
and I realize that though I went to school,
但我发现学校中的很多社交
and I know a lot of the socialization
并没有多好 多积极
is not positive socialization in school.
你也看到了 我们街坊邻居
But you can see, I mean, the neighborhood that we live in
并不怎么样  所以 我们就适当跟他们保持距离
is not that great and so we've kind of kept our distance
不过 这也不是说
from the people who live...And it's not anything like,
呃 我们 就觉得自己有多好
oh, we... you know,we think we're great
或者说他们不好
or they're not all right.
不是那样 只是 我自己
It's not that,it's just, you know, for me
不是这么长大成人的
it's not how I was raised.
我在中西部长大
I grew up in the Midwest,
生活在农场里
And I lived in the middle of the farm country.
小心
Careful.
嗯 所以 我们也想让他们 ……
Yeah, so, you know,we try to keep them like, uh...
也稍微远离点社会喧嚣
just a little bit removed from that.
穆昆达做的这个 我做的这个
Mukunda made this,and I made this.
结果做的不太好
This turned out not that good.
看见这个了么
See this?
想要放子弹时   就会发现其实是这样打开的
When they open to put bullets,it actually can open like that.
- 这是披头士乐队吗？ - 对 是披头士
- Is that The Beatles? - Yeah, that's The Beatles.
我爸爸放音乐超大声 他喜欢音乐
My father puts loud music.He loves music.
- 我觉得他喝多了 - 可能
- I think he drank too much wine. - Maybe.
嗯  他到现在都还没出屋呢
Yeah, actually, he hasn't come out of the room yet, so...
他就像个嬉皮士
He's like a hippy, you know?
不喜欢跟别人过多交往
And he doesn't like socializing too much.
就像是…
He's very like a little sort of...
怎么说呢  跟周围人格格不入
How do you say, isolated,like, around people.
我过感恩节就跟意大利人似的
I have thanksgiving like an Italian.
吃啊吃啊吃 说话就像个流氓
I eat and eat and eat and talk like a gangster.
感恩节快乐 干杯
Happy thanksgiving and salud .
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Salud. - Salud.
- 感恩节快乐 - 感恩节快乐
- Happy Thanksgiving. - Happy Thanksgiving.
我爸爸 他不喜欢工作
My father, he doesn't love the idea of working.
他说这就叫成了社会的奴隶
He calls it being a slave to society.
这个国家有问题
This is a country gone wrong.
他就是那种认为
He's one of those people that believe that
政府就是一卑鄙的组织
the government is a sneaky organization
我们全都被控制着 都像机器人一样
That we're all controlled,we're all like robots,
我们需要 挣脱这种束缚
and that we need to break free from that,
所以 他就不工作 来以示反抗
and he shows his rebellion by not working.
但他喜欢音乐
But he loves the idea of music.
他总想 "要是我们能签份唱片合约
He was like, "if we could get a record contract
玩音乐做专辑 那多好"
and play music for albums,you know,that's different."
这是我们妈妈长头发的时候
This is our mother when she had longer hair.
那是谁 是你吗
Who's that?Is that you?
是我
That's me.
我总是在想 她为什么会爱上他
I've always wondered why she fell in love with him
他又为什么会爱上她
and why he fell in love with her,
我就想 怎么会呢？
like, how did that happen?
他们都不是一个国家的
They're like from two separate countries.
我妈妈告诉我 是因为她当时想
From what my mom tells me is that she wanted
去南美玩儿 所以她走了很多地方
to visit South America,so she was traveling a lot,
就遇到了这群人
and she met this group of people.
他们就像 背包客
They were like... hikers.
对印加古道很了解 他就是其中一个
They knew the Inca trail well,and he was one of them.
非常自由随意的感觉 留着长头发
Very free style, you know.They wore their hair long.
他们对当地很熟悉  可以给人当导游的那种
They knew the place, like,they would give people tours,
尤其是美国白人
especially white Americans.
而且 他也挺有魅力的
Besides him being you know, charming,
又亲切 很会搭讪
and very friendly,he was... he had a way about hi
谦谦君子的感觉
that was, like,very unassuming.
感觉 我不想...
It felt like I didn't want to just...
跟那种只关心
Be with someone or be interested in someone
要买什么样的新衣服
who was only concerned about, you know,
该买哪种滑雪板的那种人交往
uh, the next new coat they were going to buy
我对那种不感兴趣
and the next new pair of skis,and what, you know,
或者该到哪个餐馆吃饭什么的
I don't know, which restaurant they were gonna eat in.
因为这种事情 对我来说 不那么重要
You know, because those things to me are not that important.
就好像 这就好像
Like it... and it just seemed like, you know,
我们确实有很有共同点
we really had a common ground there
在看待事情上
for how we thought about things.
还有我们 是怎么
And what we... what we thought about, you know,
看待今世的
what this life is.
还有 应该怎么生活
You know, and how life should be lived, you know.
我当时想 噢 这个人看待事物
I thought, oh, this is somebody who really sees things
是真的是不同于
in a different way than most of the people
我所认识的一般人
that I had acquaintance with.
我爸爸总认为自己比别人都强
My dad always thought that he was better than anybody.
他自己总是这么说
He always said so himself.
他说他就是神 是大彻大悟了的
He said he was God.He said he was enlightened.
说自己 无所不知
He said he was the one who knew everything.
嗯  可以说在父亲身边长大
Well, I think I can say that the most positive thing
对我来说最大的好处就是
that came growing up with our father
就是
was, for me anyway is...
我总是  我会思考很多
I always, you know,I thought a lot.
因为 我们不是很放得开
Because we weren't so open,you know,
小时候不是很外向
like outwardly in our childhood.
我经常都是在脑子里想
I was always in my head.
很多事我都记得
I remember a lot.
这件事我其实挺有怨气的
It's one thing I have that I kind of curse at.
我们小时候总是担惊受怕
We were frightened kids,
因为在你还小的时候  你看见什么 也没有概念
like you're a kid,you're just seeing things.
不知道什么意思  但是你会害怕
You don't know what it means but it frightens you.
我就很害怕
So I was frightened.
这是我最早的记忆之一了
That's one of the first memories I have.
因为我能听到 爸爸妈妈在吵架
'Cause I would hear dad and mom arguing.
经常能听到一个巴掌扇过去…
There was always a slap,just...
他会扇她耳光
he would slap her.
她的痛苦 有时我能感同身受
What she felt,we felt sometimes.
因为我们都同在一个屋檐下
I mean,we were part of it.
换做是你
If you're living in that kind of situation,
你也能感受到
you're gonna get it, too.
以下为电影《黑暗骑士》片段
看着我 看着我
Look at me.look at me!
哥谭 DC漫画虚拟城市
你看到哥谭市疯狂成什么样了么 这都是拜蝙蝠侠所赐
You see this is how crazy Batman's made Gotham.
想要哥谭市恢复秩序 蝙蝠侠必须摘下面具
You want order in Gotham,Batman must take his mask off
投案自首
and turn himself in.
他若不从 每天都会有人因此而死
Oh, and every day he doesn't,people will die,
今晚生效
Starting tonight.
我是个言出必行的人
I'm a man of my word.
我来见布鲁斯 韦恩
I'm here to see Bruce Wayne?
对不起 韦恩先生不接听未预约的电话
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne doesn't take unscheduled calls.
是父亲 把电影
Our father is the one that brought movies
带进了我们生活
into our lives.
他就这样让我们成天满脑子都是电影
He'd just fill our heads with movies all day long.
我们差不多 有
We've got like,I don't know,
5000部电影  有录像  有DVD
5,000 movies including VHS's, DVD's.
我想 我们之所以会觉得
And I think the fact that we went with the idea
会有另一个世界存在
That there's another world out there,
是因为我们不知道这个世界什么样
because we didn't know the world,
所以我们差不多就是没有世界
so we kind of had no world,
我想 是电影帮我们创造了
and I think the movies helped us create
一个我们自己的世界
our own kind of world.
但我们是知道
But we would always know the difference
现实生活跟电影是不同的
between real life and the movies.
这些道具都是用麦片盒
This outfit is made out of cereal boxes
和瑜伽垫做的
and yoga mats.
这个是瑜伽垫 这个硬的部分
That's a yoga mat and the hard parts you see
是麦片盒的纸壳做的
is cardboard from cereal boxes.
演的时候  我们必须
When we do it,I have to get in the mind
融入到角色中去
of the character.
演蝙蝠侠  我就必须要表现的非常强壮才行
I have to be as strong as I can be to play Batman,
因为这算是一种责任
'Cause it's a responsibility,sort of.
有些人可能觉得这挺可悲的
That sounds pathetic to some people because...
但对我们世界 我们自己来说
But to us and to our world
是我们特有的消遣
it is very personal.
看完《黑暗骑士》后
After I saw The Dark Knight
我开始相信
that made me believe that something
有些事是可能发生的
was possible to happen,
并不是因为他是蝙蝠侠
not because it was Batman,
是因为这就像另外一个世界
it's because it felt like another world.
为了能让那个世界成真 好逃离我现在的世界
I did everything I could to make that world come true
我不遗余力
to escape my world.
我十五岁时
I was 15 years old
连走出自己家门都不行
and I wasn't allowed to walk out my front door.
我不能
I wasn't allowed to...
随意去想去的房间
go in a specific room I felt like going in.
不能
I wasn't allowed to leave a room
随便离开房间
when I wanted to.
他让我们待在哪个房间 我们就得待在哪个房间
If he put us in a room, we have to stay there
直到说可以走为止
until he says you can go.
只有父亲有开大门的
Our dad was the only one that had the keys
钥匙
to the front door,
别人都没有 连母亲都没有
no one else, not even our mother.
除非母亲要去赴约什么的
Unless our mother went to an appointment or something,
还得是很紧急的那种
if it was an emergency.
当你都不再想着要逃出藩篱了
It's scary not having...
其实挺可怕的
Having to want to break out of that, that box.
2010年 一月的一个星期六
It was a Saturday on January, 2010.
当时我十五岁
I was 15 back then.
早上九点半 十点左右起了床
I woke up by like 9:30 or 10:00.
穿上黑外套
I got dressed up in black.
直接打开门 对我幺弟
I just unlocked the door and just said
加哥迪沙说 祝我好运
to my youngest brother Jagadisa, "wish me luck".
我戴了面具 这样别人就认不出我来了
I wore the mask so nobody would recognize me,
谁都认不出来
nobody at all,
当时正好家里没吃的了
and my father was out that day getting food,
所以父亲就出门买食品去了
'cause we were low on food.
他得买很多东西
And he was going out to get a lot of food.
一般得三个小时左右
So he usually is gone three hours when he gets foods
就是 突如其来的一股子冲动
and, uh, I just had this urge to all of a sudden,
就想要自己出门去 不想任何人认出我
just go out on my own have no one recognize me,
就算是父亲看着我了 也认不出来
and if my father saw me, he wouldn't know it was me.
走了大概两个街区
Went around two blocks
漫无目的的逛商店
just going in whatever store.
去银行 去杂货铺
Went into a bank, went into a grocery store,
去药店
went into a pharmacy.
最后 有人报警了
Eventually, someone called the cops
因为大街上有人戴着个面具 那是...挺瘆人的
'cause someone in a mask, that... that's not normal.
此处指迈克尔基顿 为89年版《蝙蝠侠》扮演者
当时 我觉得自己就像迈克尔一样
But I felt like I was Michael at that time.
但我问我自己
And I just thought to myself, you know,
我能挨得起枪子么
can I survive bullets?
呃...之后
Um... well, one thing led to another.
警察就把我拷了起来
They handcuffed me and, uh...
押着我...进了电梯
We went to... we went in the elevator.
然后回到了我住的地方
We went to where I live,
但他们说我得去医院
but they said I'm gonna have to go to a hospital,
其实是最后 他们硬带着我
And, uh... Well, they ended up just taking me
去了医院 所以说...
to the hospital, so...
这事儿也有好的一面
There was a good side to this.
因为那是我哥哥有生以来第一次
'Cause this is first time my brother started connecting
跟别人接触
with other people
虽然接触的是医院里的病人 挺悲催的
and it was sadly the patients of the hospital.
但是病人里也有些人 没那么疯
But some of them, not all of them, were like crazy, crazy,
不像《飞越疯人院》那种
not like the "cuckoo's nest."
跟电影里不太一样
It was different.
基本上 就是那种有自杀倾向的孩子
It was more like suicidal kids,
活的不开心的
kids who weren't happy with their life,
抑郁的
kids who were depressed,
他在那儿发生了不少事儿
and he had a whole story there,
不过 他也给那地方带去了不少欢乐
but he brought a lot of joy to the hospital, kind of.
他回家时 我们都很高兴
We were really happy that he came home.
给他做了顿大餐 庆祝他出院
We all baked a meal for his return,
其实就是千层面啦
which is lasagna always.
这种时候一般都是吃千层面 因为我们都吃爱千层面
It's always lasagna' cause we love lasagna.
那时我特怕回家
I was scared to come home.
我觉得爸爸肯定被我吓坏了
I think my daddy was frightened of what I just did.
因为别人都没这样过
because no one had ever done that.
就是那天
That was the day.
我就此卸下了孝子牌坊
I kind of like tore off the soldier necklace
彻底丢掉
and threw it and walked away.
打那天起 我跟我父亲说 我不会再和你说话
Since that day, I said I refuse to talk to you.
我不要再听你的了
I refuse to take your orders.
我们从此断绝父子关系
We're no longer father and son anymore.
不好意思 一想到当时
I'm sorry, it brings a lot...
就有些激动
of emotion just thinking about it back then.
我不会哭的
I'm not gonna cry.
你们有谈过到外面去么
Did you guys ever talk about going outside?
- 自己出去？ - 对
- By ourselves? - Yeah.
你知道穆昆达以前有过这打算么
Like, did you know Mukunda was gonna do that?
- 不知道 - 有谁知道吗
- No. - Did anybody know?
没有 没谁知道
No, nobody knew that.
可能他提过这茬吧 不过...
Maybe he mentioned it, but...
我们没想到...没觉得他是认真的
We weren't... like, we didn't think he was serious.
因为我们经常说这说那
'Cause we all used to say a lot of things
但都是纸上谈兵
But we never did anything.
我们一直都觉得不会有好事发生
We always saw a bad thing coming,
像是 不会有好结果的
like, it's not gonna end up well.
但问题是 我们也无能为力
The thing is we couldn't do anything about it.
我们唯一能做就是
The only thing we could do about it
就是...捱过去...
was just... get through it...
不要崩溃
and... not break.
我想大多数人经历这种日子后
I think like most people would go insane
都会疯掉的
after experiencing a life like that
但我们都没有
whereas all of us didn't...
我想 应该多亏妈妈吧
I think it's... it's because of our mom.
她能...让我们还能保持理智
She always... kept our sanity.
我爱她她也爱我
I love her and she loves me
他这样 会让他自己
He put himself in a position
坐上十年的牢的
where he was gonna have to to do ten years in prison.
他是在作死
that's what he did.
奎师那把自己的眉毛剃掉了
Krsna shaved his eyebrows.
可能他躲着不出来就是因为这个吧
It's probably why he doesn't want to show himself.
哦  他在这呢
Oh, he's right here.
你把眉毛剃了
You shaved your eyebrows.
是啊
Yeah.
挺新鲜的哈  秃眉毛 笨手笨脚
So that's new, eyebrows, I got a bad hand.
笨手笨脚
I got a bad hand.
- 你怎么样？ - 挺好的
-How you doing? -I'm doing good.
是么？
Yeah?
我刚正和克里斯多说我俩以前总打架
Yeah, I was just telling Crystal how much we fight.
我出院后他们给我安排了个心理医生
They gave me a therapist after I got out of the hospital.
他们说我应该看心理医生
They said I should see a therapist.
她帮我注册了个邮箱
She's helped me out getting my email address
因为我一点也不懂电脑
'Cause I knew nothing about computers,
所以她确实帮了我不少忙
So she's been kind of a help.
她确实
She has.
我哥哥弟弟们也去她那儿看
My brothers are also seeing her.
感觉挺逊的
It sucks.
我不怎么说心里话
I don't really talk about my feelings.
我不...她  不知道
I don't... she doesn't... She has no idea
我是什么样的人
of the kind of person I am.
所以我一般就只是在那 对 是啊 是啊
I'm like, "yeah, yeah, yeah,
管你说什么呢
whatever you tell me, you know."
家庭工会和我们有争执  就是
Our family union has a problem with now
他们想让我们去学校上学
is that they want us to go to a real school.
打死我也不会去
Over my dead body they will.
他们别想把我弄到学校去
They ain't gonna make me go to a real school.
妈妈会没活干的
My mother would be out of a job.
她就得到街上
She would have to then work in the streets,
到外面去工作
work out there.
我不会让妈妈去外面工作的
I'm not letting my mother work out there.
在纽约这种地方 不 不行
New York, no, no, not in New York.
她在家更好 她能领到钱
She's more together here. She gets paid.
我们每个月都能领到些钱
We get paid every month
因为她算是在家教我们读书 那也算是份工作
because she's homeschooling, so it's like she has a job.
当然 她是有教师认证的
She's approved, of course, to be a teacher.
她有个执照那样的东西
She has like the license and everything.
他们准许她 在家教课
They approved her, house of education.
所以家庭工会就没法再找事儿了
So that family union can't do crap or anything.
你是FBI探员
You're an FBI agent.
你是负责哪块来着？
What is your specialty again?
化学武器 别提了
Chemical weapons. Don't mention that.
那些中途要去蒙古的
You're going all the way from Tibet to Mongolia,
你们大老远从西藏跑过去
says it'll cut five hours out of the trip
还不得花上五个小时啊[这句笑点有些奇怪，自己get...]
for everybody that's going there.
我真正想要 真正希望的...
What I really wanted and what I really saw...
我以为 当我抚养孩子时
I really thought that when I was raising my children
应该会是在一个  绿野田园那样的地方
that they would be growing up in a place with,
...抚养他们长大
you know, green fields and...
但他们没能过上
But they didn't have that.
我觉得因为 我是那样长大的
And you know, I feel... because I had that,
所以我希望他们也能那样
and I wanted that for them.
就是能出去 到森林里去漫步
You know, and to be able to go out and roam the forest,
对我来说
that was important to me and, um,
能到田野里去玩儿
you know, just to go out and play in a field
或者是 那种鸡犬相闻的地方
or have someplace, some fields that were close,
就像电影里常出现的那种
or, you know, how you see in movies.
孩子们会跑到邻居的牧场
You know, kids go running through the neighbor's meadow
去他们的...森林...
you know, to get to their... the forest
造几个树屋 那样的生活
that they built some tree house in or something like that...
才是我向往的
Something like that.
我一直都希望他们能过这样的生活
I'd always thought I wanted that for them.
但没能实现
But it didn't happen.
我哥哥又出走了一次 就那么出去了
My brother did it again, just walked out,
然后 我也 自己就那么出去了
and then suddenly I went out
但父亲没有生气
and my father didn't get angry,
所以我们大家都开始时不时出门
and then all of us started doing it.
我们决定来一次
We decided to go as a group together alone
集体出行
for the first time.
他们渐渐地开始
That whole process of them getting
一点点独立
into their own happened gradually
那并不是那种 前一天还规行矩步
It's not like it was one day they followed the rules
然后 第二天就突然变了
and the next day they were doing whatever.
不是那样的
It wasn't like that.
而是慢慢改变 并非一朝一夕
It happened over a period of months,
但这绝对开启了一道通往常人世界的大门
but it certainly opened the way to normalcy.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
难道他会以为等到我们大家都长大了
Well, what did he expect when all of us become of age,
还会一直听他的不成？
we're still gonna do things his way?
他整个人就像个定时炸弹
His system was just like a ticking bomb.
我很理解 非常理解
I really understand, totally,
他们会有那种想法
you know, where they're coming from,
但是我很难 就那么坦然承认
But I can't, you know, be too candid about that.
可能 我的规矩要更多一些
But, yeah, there were probably more rules for me
比他们还多
than there were for them.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
- 看那个！- 哇哦！
-  Look at that. - Whoa!
眼睛都要爽爆了
That fucks your eyes.
就跟3D似的
This is like 3D, man.
看那个 看那些树畸不畸形
Look at that.Look at those freaky trees.
- 就想想那些树叶 - 那些树好大
- Think about all the leaves. - Those are big fucking trees.
看起来就像是...我觉得我自己就好像...在法贡森林里
They look like... I feel like I'm in like the Fangorn Forest.
《魔戒》里的那个
In The Lord of the Rings
哦 外面空气真清新
Oh, it's very fresh  out here.
- 你下去游个泳不？ - 不想
- You want to go for a swim? - No.
妈的一路游到布鲁克林得多爽
No, what swim all the way to the fuckin' Brooklyn?
以下为电影《低俗小说》片段
你是朱尔斯吧
You must be Jules,
那你就是文森特了
which would make you Vincent.
我想的快 说得快 你们要是想
I think fast, I talk fast And I need you guys
摆脱这烂摊子  就得麻利着点儿
to act fast if you want to get out of this.
所以 拜托了
So pretty please, with sugar on top,
快他妈把那车洗干净了
clean the fucking car.
别那么瞅着我 行不
Don't be looking at me like that, all right?
我知道你怪我
I can feel your look.
哦 老兄  就你干的这蠢事儿 我他妈记你一辈子
Oh, man, I will never forgive your ass for this shit!
真他妈的有够蠢
This is some fucked up repugnant shit.
朱尔斯 你听过那么句话没
Jules, did you ever hear of the philosophy that
知错能改
once a man admits he is wrong,
善莫大焉？
he's forgiven for all his wrongdoings?
听过没？
You ever hear that?
少他妈来这套
Get the fuck out of my face with that shit!
说这话的傻逼
Motherfucker who said that shit,
是他妈的不会因为你
never had to pick up 80 pieces of brain
在这他妈的挑死人骨头
on account of your dumb ass.
我是有脾气的 朱尔斯
I got a threshold, Jules.
忍无可忍 我可是要翻脸的
I got a threshold for the abuse that I will take.
- 我会爆发的 - 哦 你准备爆发了？
- I could blow. - Oh, you're ready to blow?
没错 要爆发了
Yeah, I'm ready to blow.
那我还他妈爆发原子弹呢
Well, I'm a mushroom-cloud- laying motherfucker,
你妈的
motherfucker!
每捡一块儿人脑子
Every time my fingers touch brain,
我他妈都想杀了你
I'm super fly TNT.
真他妈凉啊
It's motherfuckin' cold, man!
好了  快点  快点 快点洗
Come on, get it out. Come on, do it.
转过去
Turn around.
- 他修好了吗 - 没有
- Did he fix this? - No.
坏了
It's broken.
是 这锁彻底玩完了
Yeah, I know that's totally busted.
想着大门开着 还没锁
I don't feel safe now
觉得好不安全
knowing that the door's open and there's no lock.
今天 发生了点儿意外
Today, we had a little surprise.
突然间 我就
Out of nowhere,
听着撞门的声儿
I just heard banging on the door.
然后我看见了...听见
and I saw a kind of...At least I heard,
听起来像是电锯声儿
it sounded like a saw...
- 在打钻  - 打钻  对
-Drilling. - Drilling, yeah.
然后在走廊这边
And by this doorway,
我看着有突击队冲进来  就是电影里那种
I see what I usually see in the movies... swat teams,
戴着头盔 盾牌 机关枪
people with helmets and shields, machine guns
破门而入
just blast in.
让我们都趴在地板上
Told everybody to get on the floor
举起手  把我们都推到墙根上去
or get their hands up, put us against the wall,
还把我们一家都拷起来了
and handcuffed every member of our family.
他们有搜查令
They had a search warrant for...
说我们私藏武器
possession of weapons.
他们要找一把枪
A gun they were looking for.
说是把点38
They said a 38.
就像《局内人》里似的
Basically, it was like Inside Man.
所有…他们能找到的武器都是道具
All... the only kind of weapons they found were props.
他们把我们的机关枪都搜出来了
They take out all our machine guns,
还有手枪啊 刀啊
all our handguns, knives,
不过那都是假的
and it was all fake.
然后 他们也算是明白了
They basically found out the kind of things
我们这点爱好
we were into.
然后就恭维了我们一番 说
And they complimented us and they said like,
不好意思随便闯进来啥的
"We're sorry about the break-in."
我们眼睁睁看着妈妈被铐起来
We had to see our mother get handcuffed...
被推到墙根
and put against the wall...
手铐弄得她
and she was really uncomfortable
那么难受
sitting in those handcuffs.
真要把我气疯了
That's what really pissed me off.
他们开始接触外面的世界 与外界交流
They've begun communicating and relating in the world.
他们可能发现了电影和现实生活虽很相像
They are probably seeing how the movies are like real,
却不是现实  还有  现实生活到底怎样的
but not real, and how the real life is.
这对于从小就受电影熏陶长大的
It's hard as a child
孩子来说 很不容易
being influenced by that.
任何事都是  过犹则不及
Too much of anything is, you know, is not good.
我觉得 他们应该就是这样
And I think that they probably had too much of that.
我们从来没坐过火车
We never took a train before.
我们一直害怕火车
We were always afraid of trains.
我们也害怕
We were always freaked out about the kind of people
那种四处闲逛的人
that hang around.
我们听说过 拦路抢劫
You know, we heard about the muggings
之类的事
and stuff like that.
挺奇怪的 我知道 不过 没办法
It is weird, I admit, but there you go.
我们不需要阳光
We don't need the sun.
我们是吸血鬼
We are vampires.
爽！
Yeah!
- 哦 沙滩在那儿  - 是啊
- Boy: Oh, there's the beach.- Yeah.
哦 天  全都是人
Oh, shit, there's people all over it.
我可不要去    奶奶的
I ain't going in there. Fuck that!
- 那你以为什么样？ - 算了吧
- What did you expect?- forget it, man.
- 就稍微躲开点儿   - 你说的容易
- Just stay a little back. - Yeah, man.
算了吧  我才不要下去
Forget it.I ain't going in that water.
我不要下水
I ain't going in that water.
噢  想想《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》
Oh, yeah, Lawrence of Arabia.
哇 好痒
Whoa, it scratches!
不知道
No idea.
- 我很怕水 - 是吗
- I'm afraid of the water.- You are?
是的
Yeah.
好咸啊
That is salty, man.
哇哦 天
Whoa, man!
正面就下去 反面就不用
Heads you go, tails you don't.
听天由命
It all comes down to this.
女生们这边走
Ladies coming this way.
来吧 哥们
Here we go, man.
要是掉地上就不算
If it drops on the floor, it doesn't matter.
好了
Right.
正面就下 反面就不下
Heads you go, tails you don't.
正面！你得下水
Heads! You go.
就跟《黑暗骑士》里的双面人似的
This is part of the Two Face in Dark Knight thing.
- 你跟我一起下去 - 没门
- You're coming with me. - No way.
丹尼 到水里来!
Danny, come in the pool!
再来一次 是反面
Call again.  Tails.
看来我是不用去了
Looks like I'm not Going anywhere.
拜托 丹尼 下一次水嘛
Come on, Danny. Come in the pool.
丹尼 下一次水嘛
Danny, come into the water.
大胆点嘛 兄弟 迈出这一步
Let's break some rules, man. Let's break some rules.
这不...不行 我不要迈步
It's not... no, I don't break rules.
上次我迈步时候  差点被抓起来 两次都是
Last time I did that, I almost got arrested, twice.
你咋这么多事儿
You have all these rules!
哦 该死 娘的
Oh, shit, son of a bitch!
- 来吧 - 不要
- Come on, man. - Nah.
- 他们都等你呢 - 不 这样挺好的
- They're all out there waiting for you. - No, it's all right.
而且 我愿意别人说
Besides, I like to be the guy everybody says,
看那人总也不下水
that guy never went in the water.
看他总也不脱鞋
That guy never took his shoes off.
你需要些阳光
♪ You need some sunshine ♪
你需要些日光
♪ You need some daylight ♪
你需要来点阳光
♪ You need some sunshine ♪
你需要来点日光
♪ You need some daylight ♪
我想 我们的父亲并不知道
I don't think our father knew we had it in us
我们内心的渴望  会那么强烈
to have that kind of power.
估计他一直把我们当什么都不懂的小屁孩来看
I guess he always saw us as the little boys who couldn't,
但我们已经长大了
and then we transformed into the boys are gonna
成人了
The boys can
噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
插曲 Tarzan Boy
噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
我来自远方 在丛林游荡
♪ Jungle life,I'm faraway from nowhere ♪
像人猿泰山
♪ On my own like Tarzan boy ♪
捉起迷藏
♪ Hide and seek ♪
林中穿梭 嬉戏徜徉
♪ I play along while rushing cross the forest ♪
明媚午后 闹剧疯狂
♪ Monkey business on a sunny afternoon ♪
噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢噢
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
我的力量影响着他们所有人
你走开
好好想想
我们现在这种生活简直猪狗不如
我不想再跟他说话
I just can't talk to him anymore.
看他一眼我都受不了
I can't stand to look at him.
每次我一看他
It's just...When I look at him,
我看到的就是
Everything I see...
他对我不满
in him feels wrong to me.
我不想让他们有压力 那种来自社会的压力
像国家利益种种
不想让他们受到太多束缚
受到毒品
或者某些学说 宗教的毒害
想让他们明白自己是谁 是什么样的人
一直以来 我都跟他们说
我不在乎你拥有多少
也不在乎你能力大小
你当下 今生 你是什么样的人
我们是什么样的人 对我来说才是最重要的
才是最重要的
嗯
Yeah.
我们当初来纽约
是想看看能不能赚到点钱
然后好去斯堪的纳亚半岛
我喜欢那儿的人 斯堪的纳维亚的
他们生活的某些方式
很好
因为他们的社会状态 体制…（很好）
但没能如愿以偿
这种生活环境 不是我们夫妻二人
想让他们过的生活
但是我们也无能为力 再负担不起其他的了
因此 我们想试着过
这种和人老死不相往来的生活
所以 我们总是  跟他们说
别担心外面怎么样
有人在电梯里贩卖毒品
可能还会死两三个人
你不明白我到底什么感受
我
一个自由人 自由身
你不明白我到底什么感受
当我看到那些人
干得那些勾当
外面简直就跟监狱没两样
孩子们这样 我很欣慰
I felt good from my kids
看到他们能坚持
I was glad to see them standing up
自己的观点 信仰  我很高兴
for their own ideas and beliefs
嘿 我就这样 这就是我的做法
Hey, this is me.I'm doing this.
两边我都想理解
I'm trying to see both sides
我自己这边也是 我都想照顾到
as well as my part in it as well
但我一直觉得有些进退两难
but I've felt stuck in the middle for a long time
真的不容易
and that's been a real challenge
如果奥斯卡能明白
If some part of Oscar understood
就是  他们为什么会叛逆
what, you know, why they were, like, rebelling
为什么他们想要我行我素
and why they were going on their own,
但另一方面 他又非常的焦虑
another part of him was like very anxious
非常担心  因为他觉得
and very worried because,you know, he felt like,
这不是...时机已经错过去了
it wasn't... the timing was off.
对大家来讲 这时机都不太好
It wasn't like the right time for everyone.
但是 我...我认为
And, you know, my...my point of view
现在 时机很好
was that, well,it must be the right time
因为 事情发生了 就是好时机
because it's happening,you know.
要不然
It's so... I mean,if it wouldn't be,
就不会发生
it wouldn't be happening.
这就是我的想法
That's how I kind of felt about it.
不错 蜘蛛侠
Well, done, Spider-man.
我们认识之前  就是在这之前 一年前吧
Before we actually met,it's like before me met,
你应该看看那时我们什么样
you should have seen us like one year before we met
我们都不说话
We would not have said a word...
一声不吭
I mean, nothing.
完全不说话的
We would have been completely silent.
就像是
It would have been like...
你知道僵尸吧
You would have been watching zombies
行尸走肉一样
Just walking by.
我刚知道谷歌这个新词
I learned that google was a new word
以前可从来没听过
that I'd never heard of
“酷炫” “老兄” “黑鬼”
"Cool", "dude", "nigger"...
哦 不好意思
Oops, sorry.
还有...对了 还有 “like”这个词
And... well, basically,"like".
比如 我去到商店
Like, I went to the store,
这里有 那种 钢琴 很酷的那种
and there was, like,these, cool pianos,
我就会说 “喔 这玩意 真  太屌了
and I was like, "whoa,that shit is, like, awesome".
我总是听到这种
So I'm hearing that all the time.
不是说多烦  就是有点过时了
It's not annoying, but it's getting old.
周一是情人节 是吧
Monday's Valentine's Day,right?
- 你有约会？ - 不 没有
-You have dates? - No, I don't.
我倒希望有
I wish I did, though.
说真的
Seriously.
我分不出来这香水是男人用的还是女人用的
I can't tell if it's women's or men's perfume.
真的分不出来
I can't really tell.
没什么区别吧   香水就香水嘛
It makes no difference, right? perfume is perfume.
我是真不知道怎么跟女生搭讪
I literally have no idea what to say to a woman.
对你们来说可能很简单 但…
I mean, it's easy for you,guys, like, but...
对我...就是真的不知道该说什么
For me it's... I don't literally don't know what to say.
你有没有听别人说过...
You ever heard about people that say... say,
这人真是不招人喜欢？
he is absolutely unlovable?
有些人就是那样的
Some people are like that.
就是天生无缘
It just doesn't happen with them.
爱就是不眷顾他们
Love just doesn't find them in life.
有的人  有的人喜欢一个人生活
Some people like that,some people want to live alone.
有的人 就喜欢和别人一起生活
Some people they really want to live with somebody,
只是他们不知道怎么...他们合不了群
only they don't know how to...They can't fit in.
- 他喝醉了 - 我爸爸喝醉了
- He's drunk. - My dad's drunk.
又喝醉了？
Again?
他昨晚就喝醉了 今晚又喝醉了
He was drunk last night.He's drunk tonight.
他可能...他真的喝太多了
He's probably... he drinks way too much,
挺无聊的
so it's a boring story anyway.
我发誓
I swear to God
我会把他带走的
I'm gonna get him back for this.
怎么了
What's going on here?
放松点
Just take it easy, okay?
天啊  他应该是晕过去了
Oh, God.I think he's losing it.
宝贝 今天晚上 就好好玩就是了   -好的
Yan, just enjoy yourself,sweetie, tonight. -Okay.
听着 额
And see, uh, you know,
和谁聊都行  认识的 不认识的
whoever you want to talk to you know or you don't know.
开心就好     -好的
You know, just enjoy yourself.-Okay.
玩的开心 加哥迪沙
Enjoy yourself,have fun, Jagadisa.
玩的开心
You have fun.
好好玩 哥文达 嗯  开心点儿
Yeah, have fun, Govinda,yeah, enjoy yourself.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
-I love you. -I love you.
再见
See you.
第一张电影票...
First tickets to a movie theater...
太兴奋了
Really exciting.
但愿我们能活着出来
I hope we come out alive.
现在开始播报新闻
Start spreading the news.
告诉我你在找什么
So tell me what you're looking for.
人人都爱高清电视
Everybody loves HDTV...
真是个好电影
That was a good movie.
今天晚上 我会 一直
I'm gonna remember this night for a long,
一直  一直 一直记着 不会忘的
Long, long, long, long,long time.
我也是
Me, too.
说真的 钱都被
And to actually think the money is gonna go
大卫·O·拉塞尔
to David O. Russell
制片人 导演
马克·沃尔伯格 还有克里斯蒂安·贝尔赚走了
or Mark Wahlberg or Christian Bale.
均为演员
太屌了
That's awesome.
真刺激
That's exciting.
演《黑暗骑士》时我扮的他
I play that guy in The Dark Knight.
是《侠影之谜》
Batman Begins.
他觉得有人在跟踪我们
He thinks there's somebody following us.
我肯定有人在跟踪我们
I guarantee there's somebody following us.
没人跟踪我们
Nobody's following us.
不 真的有人跟踪我们 算了 算了
No, there's nobody following us.Forget it, forget it.
还记得以前  一想到要接触外面的世界
I remember being very kind of scared
就特别害怕
of going out into the world.
感觉自己太格格不入了
I felt so out of place.
现在我也这么觉得
I still feel out of place.
我不知道自己能不能克服这种感觉
I don't know if I can ever get over it.
因为我总觉得 我对这世界
Because I was always afraid that I had so little knowledge
实在知之甚少
of this world.
我一直都待在家里
I mean, being in my home all the time that...
我甚至都不知道 该从何开始
That I almost wouldn't... that I wouldn't know where to start.
我常常出去  想要实现我想要的
I kept going out and trying to achieve what I wanted,
做我想做的事
trying to do what I want to.
但我最怕的就是...
But my biggest fear was, you know,
因为对世界一无所知...
being so... so ignorant of the world that...
我可能根本无所适从
that I would just wouldn't be able to handle it.
你想过要和他们说对不起吗
Did you ever think of saying sorry to them?
我跟他们都说了
我觉得…他们…我希望
那种事情不会发生
但我也无可奈何
所以  我想 就由得他们吧
他们自己会判断 思考
我觉得他们已经能够了解
虽然…我…不希望那种事
嗯   不是说 我 想要
You know, like, you know that I wanted that, you know.
那种事情发生
我们是现实生活的受害者
我们知道
但我们并不怨天尤人
不相互指责
所以 我觉得
耶稣基督 就是这样看待万物的
我想 这就应该是他看事情的方式了
原谅世人
不会与谁为敌
慈悲为怀 因为他们没意识到自己所作所为（多么可耻）
发生了（就罢了)
我们会越来越好的 我是这么想 这么觉得的
我觉得我们不会退步
因为我们在成长 也在学习
在学习中成长
我不想再面对我父亲了
I gave up on facing my father.
我觉得指望他会变
And I don't think there's any good chance
是不太可能了
for him to change...
过去的事是没法改变的
Not with the things that happened.
有时候有些事你真的...
Sometimes there are things that you just...
你真的没办法.. 没办法放下
You just don't for...You just don't get over.
你真的没办法原谅
You just don't forgive.
有些事你没办法就那么抛到脑后
There are some things you just don't put behind you.
就是
It's...
有些事
There are some things...
有些人...你就是无法忍受
that peop... that you just can't live with.
好的 露西跳上来了
Okay, Lucy's jumped in.
没事 我抱着她呢  你抱着
It's okay, I can take her. You take her.
什么？
What?
哦 什么时候？
Oh, when?
哦 嗯哼
Oh, aha.
真的？
You are?
你声音一点都没变
You know, you sound the same.
和五十年前一样
You sound the same that you did 50 years ago.
我想
Well, I just...
嗯 我想说 妈妈 我很爱你
Well, I just want to say that I love you so much, mom.
真的 我真的很爱你
You know,I just love you so much.
我想说...我从来...都
But I just want to say that I've... you know, it's like...
都没有忘记过你
It's not like I've ever forgotten you.
我从没有...我时刻都想着你
I've never... I've always thought about you
你永远都在我心上
and you've always been in my, you know, my thoughts.
嗯
Yes.
嗯 我知道你都经历了什么
Um, well, I know exactly what you went through.
我有七个孩子 我...
I have seven children,and I...
嗯 真的
Yes, I do.
噢 妈妈 能听到你声音我太高兴了
Oh, mom,it's so good to hear you.
给你打了电话 我太开心了
I'm so glad I called you.
嗯 好的 好的
Yeah, sure, all right.
好的 我爱你 妈妈
All right, I love you, mom.
谢谢  好的 再见
Thank you, all right, bye-bye.
好
Yes!
棒    棒   太好了！
Yes, yes, yes!
猜怎么着
Guess what?
妈妈刚给她妈妈打电话了
Mom just talked to her mom.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
- You did?- Yeah.
她刚在密歇根跟我通的电话
Yeah, I called her in Michigan.
然后呢
So what now?
噢 她马上就上飞机
Oh, she's gonna hop on a plane
明天就到
and she'll be here tomorrow.
明天她就到这里啦
She's going to be here tomorrow.
- 喔！ - 太好了
- Whoa! -Yeah.
她  我太震惊了
She was like, "whoa, this is a shock."
我真的很想见她   嗯 嗯
I want to meet her. Yeah, yeah.
老头子知道你打电话给她了吗
Does the old man know you called her?
嗯 他知道我要打电话给她
Yeah, he knows that I was gonna call her.
他怎么说
How's he taking it?
没看到他出去了么
That's why he went out.
他什么毛病
What's his problem?
嗯  他可能害怕他们会
Well, you know, he's afraid that they're gonna
会干什么吧
you know, do something and make problems.
他们能干什么
What are they gonna do?
-不知道 - 都是一家人 是你的家人
-I don't know.  They're family.They're your family.
我知道 嗯 他害怕
I know, well, he's afraid
因为他们以前确实找过点麻烦
because they made problems before a long time ago.
是他找麻烦吧
He was the one that was making the problem not them.
嗯 打了电话 太好了
Yeah, I'm so glad that I called.
那个... 感觉就像  向恐惧屈服
That... you know, it's like,oh, giving in to my fears
老是想要是这样怎么办 要是那样怎么办？
or what if this, or what if that?
不知道怎么说 就是
And I don't know, you know,it's like,
哦 这样做可能不好 那样做也不好
oh, this could be bad and that could be bad.
其实  嗯  可能不好 但也可能很好
And, yeah, it could be bad and it could be very good.
要是不去做 你就不会知道结果
You know, and you just don't know until you do it.
你好啊 小猫咪
Hello, kitty cat.
我听说有个叫蔓迪的网站
I heard about this website called Mandy.
我发了个帖子  说我要找私人助理工作
So I posted that I'm looking for P.A. jobs,
就突然看到这个了
and this job popped up.
我想看看我们四个里面
I just wanted to see of all the four of us,
有多少人看过《权力的游戏》
how many of us watch Game of Thrones?
看过的举手
Raise your hands.
我通宵看的
I do it all in the night.
有谁看过《绝命毒师》
Anyone here watch Breaking Bad?
- 我刚看完 - 我也看完了
-I finished that recently. -I finished it, too.
我三天看了三季
I saw three seasons in three days,
第四 第五 还有第六季
four, five and six.
我都快要看疯了
It made me fucking crazy.
你想放哪里
Where do you want it?
放到我房间来 还得上五个台阶
It's going up to my room,which is another five stairs.
- 放这里？ - 对
-Up there? -Yeah.
这就是你晚上要睡的地方？
So this is where you'll sleep tonight?
对啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
在这房间 估计不了少撞头了
There's gonna be a lot of head bumping in this room.
你还得注意下安全问题
You should also take a look at your defenses
免得被人抢劫
In case a robbery happens.
这个屌
This one's bitchin'.
这个
This one...
哦 我要拿那个回去 这个比较屌
Oh, I'll take that back,this one's bitchin'.
我知道我肯定会想他们的
I know I'm gonna miss them,
不过... 我觉得
but... I think, like,the universe reacts
一切顺其自然
to your wishes.
时机成熟时  我会把妈妈接过来
I'll bring my mom over when the time's right.
但现在 我要好好享受一下这种感觉
But right now, I'm just gonna enjoy this for a little bit.
这是新生之始
♪ Is this the end of the beginning? ♪
歌曲 End of the begining
还是旧时之终
♪ Or the beginning of the end? ♪
失控 还是全胜
♪ Losing control or are you winning? ♪
你是活出真我 还是自欺欺人
♪ Is your life real or just pretend? ♪
反转命运之轮
♪ Reanimation of the sequence ♪
将未来倒带 回到故往
♪ Rewinds the future to the past ♪
去追寻答案之源
♪ To find the source of the solution ♪
重塑这一切吧
♪ The system has to be recast ♪
试着把手放下来
Try and set your arms down if you can.
看能不能抱住胸部
See if you can cover your chest.
能拉一下吗
Can you pull it?
我在制作我自己的电影
I'm working on my own film.
是说一个人坐在椅子上
It's about this man sitting in a chair
看着窗外 不同的情绪不断浮现
and looking through a window as different feelings go by...
愤怒 悲伤 快乐 还有爱意
like anger, grief,happiness and love.
你觉得这个代表什么
What does this look like to you?
恐惧 痛苦... 惊吓？
Like fear, anguish...In shock?
惊吓？ 对 对
In shock? Yeah, yeah.
家里人大部分都会 出现在里面
My family is gonna be in it, most of them,
这个女孩 克洛伊 很可爱的
and this girl, Chloe,who's really cute
她也可以很性感
and she can be sexy, too.
- 准备好来个特写了吗？ - 准备好了
-Are you ready for your close-up? -I'm ready.
好   我们开始拍吧
Okay, let's get this show on the road.
好  你们
All right, guys.
拍克洛伊了
Let's get Chloe.
好
Okay.
哦 小心 这边走
Oh, careful, this moves.
基本上 都是恐惧
It was all fear,basically.
恐惧
The fear was...
深入到…
was put in...
我现在还是会恐惧
And I still have fear.
到今天为止 我还是恐惧
I still have fear to this day.
但谁不是呢  所以...
But who doesn't? So...
是克莱斯勒大厦
It's the Chrysler building.
看那个山坡
Look at that hillside there.
看那
Look at that.
看那个山坡
Look at that hillside.
那边... 看 你看一下
That is... look,would you look at that?
太美了
That is beautiful.
哦 看那边
Oh, look at that.
哦 老天 看那些大南瓜
Oh, jeez,look at those big pumpkins!
孩子们肯定喜欢
The kids are loving them.
在我大限之日前
Before the day I die
有五样东西我要上
There's five things I want to ride
此处的ride有 乘坐 骑 以及 ”上“的意思
自行车 三轮车 摩托车
Bicycle, tricycle,automobile
处子之母 还有摩天轮
Virgin's mother and a Ferris wheel
我想当个空军游骑兵
I want to be an airborne ranger
我得戒烟了
I got to quit smoking.
哦  太好吃了
Oh, that's so damn good.
可能是最好吃的苹果了
It's probably the best damn apple
我从来没吃过这么好吃的
I've ever tasted in my life.
我想...我希望能住在这种地方
I could live... I wish I could Live in a place like this.
可能更远一点
Maybe a little further away...
突然冒出的想法 不过
Out of nowhere, but...
这地方真的不错
It's very nice out here.
很高兴妈妈在这儿
I'm grateful my mom's here.
我一直想和她这样旅行一次
I always wanted to go on a trip like this with her.
快点 奎师那
Come on, Krsna.
看他们在干嘛呢 去看看他们在干嘛
See what they're doing. Let's go see what they're doing.
他们没事啦
They're okay.
那又怎样
Yeah, so what, you know,
我们从来没一整天都呆在一起
We haven't been around them all day.
和他们待在一起真好
It's all right to be around them,
去看看他们在干嘛
See what they're doing.
好吧
Yeah.
嗯...走吧 我想去看看他们在干嘛
Yeah... Come on, I want to see what they're doing.
快点 奎师那
Come, Krsna.
一直 离开这 离开那的 还挺难受的
It's hard to go off and go off and go off.
咱们俩从来没机会
You and me haven't had a chance
一起在果园里散步
to walk through the orchards together.
是啊...嗯 还没有过 没错 穆昆达
Yeah... yeah, not yet,that's right, Mukunda.
出界了
That's out.
好球！
Nice!
扔这个
Hit this one.
狼群